Finding Aid for Michigan Organization for Human Rights Records 1970-1995
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Michigan Organization for Human Rights Records 1973-1994
Michigan Organization for Human Rights.
A coalition of state and local human rights organizations, served as resource, lobbying and educational agent for organizations and individuals engaged in struggle to eliminate all forms of discrimination, gay and lesbian rights became an early focus of MOHR. Records document founding and administration of the organization and numerous, legislative lobbying efforts and other activities.
85287 Bj 2
13 linear feet in 14 boxes
1 oversize folders
199 GB online
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
This record group was donated by the Michigan Organization for Human Rights (donor no. 6933 ) in May 1983; material was added in February and September 1994. The Robert Lundy papers (donor no. 8756 ) were added in 1998, 2001 and 2004. Michael Perron (donor no. 8839 ) donated Gay Rights history course audio recordings in 2000.
The record group is open to research, however researchers must read and sign the MOHR Access Agreement.
The collection contains audio tapes from which digital copies have been made. Source tapes are for staff use only. Audio files are only available in the Bentley Historical Library reading room on designated Bentley Library computers.
Digitization: The Library has undertaken the digitization of a number of sound recordings within this collection. The resulting audio files are available for playback only in the Bentley Library Reading Room. Links to item images and additional information are available within this finding aid. Original sound recordings are only available for staff use.
After a series of meetings of its Steering Committee in Detroit during the Summer of 1977, the Michigan Organization for Human Rights (M.O.H.R.) was founded officially at an organizing conference attended by approximately 50 people and held in Lansing, Michigan, on October 15 and 16, 1977. The mission of the organization was broadly conceived, so that it could serve as a resource for the numerous local, state, and national human rights organizations engaged in the struggle to eliminate discrimination in all forms. Although civil rights for lesbians and gay men were not to be the sole focus of the organization, the provision of educational materials and legal advice concerning issues surrounding sexual orientation was identified from the outset as a primary goal for the organization.
In its early years M.O.H.R. meetings rotated around the state, primarily in the southeast. In September 1978, a staffed office was established in Detroit and an executive director was hired to guide the organization's lobbying, outreach, and fundraising efforts. By 1979, the funding of a staffed office and time commitments required for M.O.H.R. work were causing unforeseen pressures on both the organization and those who directed it. The resulting resignation of the first executive director led to the first in a series of reorganizations. The dependence of M.O.H.R. on financial contributions from its constituent organizations proved untenable and, by the early 1980s, the organization had shifted its primary appeal to individual members.
Although very effective in the political arena, as evidenced by the success of the M.O.H.R.-directed Michigan Privacy Challenge (1988-1990), the organization continued to be plagued with personality conflicts and clashes over its financial commitments and priorities. The latter half of the 1980s were marked by frequent resignations, reform proposals, and dire predictions from factions of the Board of Directors.
The organization met with many successes in its attempts to keep both the public and lawmakers informed about issues of concern to Michigan's lesbian and gay communities. Arguably, M.O.H.R.'s greatest success was the Michigan Privacy Challenge (1988-1990), a series of lawsuits filed by the organization on behalf of individual plaintiffs that challenged the constitutionality of Michigan's sodomy and gross indecency laws. The Wayne County Circuit Court's decision in 1990 supported M.O.H.R.'s position and was not appealed by the State of Michigan.
Other successful M.O.H.R. accomplishments include several court cases involving the rights of lesbian mothers and of persons with AIDS; continuous lobbying of the Michigan legislature for increased funding of AIDS research, education, and care; lobbying several Michigan municipalities for domestic partnership and non-discrimination ordinances; and helping to organize annual Pride Parades in southeastern Michigan. In the area of education, M.O.H.R. maintained a presence on both radio and cable television as a means of informing the public about issues concerning discrimination based on sexual preference and about the prevention and treatment of AIDS.
Despite these successes, the political and interpersonal struggles occurring throughout the 1980s resulted in mistrust and bad feelings toward the organization among its constituents in southeastern Michigan. Combined with the founding of new lesbian and gay male social and political organizations in the area's urban centers, this led to a diminution of M.O.H.R.'s political effectiveness and fundraising capabilities. After one final reorganization attempt, the Michigan Organization for Human Rights disbanded in Spring 1994.
In 1973, WDET-Detroit began airing a weekly radio program, "Gayly Speaking," which continued until 1982. As Detroit's first radio program "by, for, and about gays and gay liberation," the program focused on such topics as coming out, oppression, religion, and gays in film, theater, literature, and music. Programs always included a news and announcement segment and often featured prominent organizations and events, such as Gay Pride Week, Detroit's Gay Community Center, and the Gay Switchboard. In 1982, WDET replaced "Gayly Speaking" with "Another Voice," a new program syndicated by M.O.H.R.
The records of the Michigan Organization for Human Rights, measuring 10 linear feet, were donated to the library by M.O.H.R. in four accessions: May 1983, February and September 1994, and September 1998. The audio materials span the time period 1973 to 1980, while the manuscript materials cover the period from 1977 through the disbanding of the organization in Spring, 1994. The records are arranged in eight series: Administrative, Correspondence, Topical, Clippings, the Robert Lundy Papers (two series), Visual Materials, and Audio Materials. The series provide documentation of the founding, growth, and topical interests of a grassroots political and social organization, including the stresses involving fundraising and personality conflicts that occurred as M.O.H.R. experienced rapid growth during the late-1970s and early-1980s.
The two Robert Lundy series (1970-1995, 4 linear feet) were donated to the library in several accessions over a period of years. There is some overlap as each series contains files on legislation, files relating to his work with M.O.H.R., and topical files on issues organizations and events with which he was active in his capacity as M.O.H.R.'s legislation officer.
Subjects:
Gay liberation movement--Michigan.; Gay men--Michigan.; Gays--Michigan.; Homosexuality in radio--Michigan.; Homosexuality--Michigan.; Lesbians--Michigan.; Michigan Organization for Human Rights.; Radio broadcasting--Michigan--Detroit.
Subjects - Visual Material:
Demonstrations--Michigan--Detroit.; Detroit (Mich.)--Demonstrations.; Detroit (Mich.)--Parades and processions.; Gay rights.; Homosexuals.; Lansing (Mich.)--Parades and processions.; Lesbians.; Michigan Organization for Human Rights.; Parades and processions--Michigan--Detroit.; Parades and processions--Michigan--Lansing.
Sound Recordings
Gayly speaking (Radio program); Gay liberation movement--Michigan--Detroit.; Homosexuality.; Gays--Attitudes.; Lesbians.; Public radio--Michigan--Detroit.; Radio programs--Michigan--Detroit.; Michigan Organization for Human Rights.
Genre/Form:
Photographs.; Sound recordings.
- Administrative 1977-1994, 1 linear feet
  (Chiefly minutes, reports, and agendas)
  The Administrative series (1977-1994, 1 linear foot) contains annual reports, meeting agendas and minutes, and correspondence relating to the activities of the M.O.H.R. administrative board (which changed official names three times) and several committees thereof. It also contains a small amount of summary financial reports and fliers and information relating to the M.O.H.R. annual meeting, as well as office policies and procedures. This series provides excellent documentation concerning M.O.H.R.'s rapid transformation from a relatively small, issue-oriented umbrella organization into a large political and social organization for all southern Michigan lesbians and gay men. It also provides information regarding the internal strife which resulted in several major reorganizations and the eventual disbanding of M.O.H.R.
  - Steering Committee/Administrative Board 1977 (Box 1)
  - Administrative Board 1978-1980, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Board of Directors 1981-1994, 17 folders (Box 1)
  - Bylaws and Policy Statements 1985-1991 (Box 1)
  - Committees
    - Elections 1979-1993 (Box 1)
    - Executive 1993 (Box 1)
    - Finance 1987-1988 (Box 1)
    - Fundraising 1982-1993 (Box 1)
    - Legal Affairs 1989-1990 (Box 1)
    - Legislative 1985-1990 (Box 1)
    - Organization (Ad Hoc) 1987 (Box 2)
    - Personnel 1988-1989 (Box 2)
    - Political Action Committee 1980-1981 (Box 2)
  - Financial Report 1991, 1993 (Box 2)
  - Lansing Office 1990-1991 (Box 2)
  - Office Procedures Undated (Box 2)
  - Organizational Histories/Background Information Undated (Box 2)
  - Treasurer's Report/Financial Statement 1978-1981, 1984-1989 (Box 2)
  - Volunteer Forms Undated (Box 2)
- Topical
  The Topical series (1977-1994, 3.2 linear feet) also retains the arrangement in which the files were received from M.O.H.R. Subjects documented by the files in this series include M.O.H.R.'s interactions with other national, state, and local lesbian and gay organizations; various legal cases in which M.O.H.R. played a role; lobbying efforts concerning Michigan legislation of interest to the organization's membership; and other projects and issues with which M.O.H.R. and its members were involved.
  - Ad Hoc Committee on HIV-infected Health Care Workers. Report 1991 (Box 2)
  - AIDS Advocacy Grant (City of Detroit, MI) 1989 (Box 2)
  - AIDS and Michigan Insurance Policies 1989-1990 (Box 2)
  - AIDS Care Connection 1989-1992, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - AIDS Care Facility 1990 (Box 2)
  - AIDS Community Alliance 1989-1993 (Box 2)
  - AIDS Education 1986 (Box 2)
  - AIDS Legal Referral Service of Michigan 1990 (Box 2)
  - AIDS Survey 1988-1993 (Box 2)
  - Alliance: Michigan's Lesbians and Gays for Human Rights (Troy, MI) 1991-1992 (Box 2)
  - Anti-Gay Violence Monitoring 1989-1990 (Box 2)
  - Attorney Referral Survey 1992 (Box 2)
  - Candidate Survey (Detroit, MI) 1985 (Box 2)
  - Coming Out Survey 1992 (Box 2)
  - Community Health Awareness Group (CHAG). Brochures Undated (Box 2)
  - Corporate Project on Responsibility 1992 (Box 2)
  - Cracker Barrel Protest Coalition 1991 (Box 2)
  - Crossroads (Cross-gender living organization, Royal Oak, MI). Brochure Undated (Box 2)
  - Curriculum on Homosexuality (Birmingham, MI, Public Schools) 1992 (Box 2)
  - Detroit Area Gay/Lesbian Council (DAGLC) 1989-1993 (Box 2)
  - Detroit Lesbian/Gay Community Center 1986-1992, 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Detroit Neighborhood Opportunity Fund. MOHR Report 1993 (Box 2)
  - Episcopal Diocese of Michigan Grant 1991 (Box 2)
  - Fair Housing 1987-1988 (Box 2)
  - Friends: Persons With AIDS/ARC/HIV+ Alliance 1990 (Box 2)
  - Gay and Lesbian Parents Coalition of Michigan (Troy, MI). Brochure Undated (Box 2)
  - Gays in the Military 1992-1993 (Box 2)
  - General Motors Protest 1990 (Box 2)
  - Grantmaking Foundation Contacts 1987-1993 (Box 2)
  - Great Lakes Gaylaxians. Bylaws 1992 (Box 2)
  - Hate Crimes 1987-1990 (Box 2)
  - Health Emergency Assistance of Detroit 1992-1993 (Box 3)
  - HIV Service Coalition 1993 (Box 3)
  - Homophobia. Robert Egan's (MOHR Vice-president) speech at Central Michigan University and student response 1992 (Box 3)
  - Human Rights Campaign Fund, Michigan Dinner 1991-1992 (Box 3)
  - Lambda Report (Public access cable TV show), 1987-1988 (Box 3)
  - Lansing Area AIDS Network (LAAN) 1992-1993 (Box 3)
  - Lansing Association for Human Rights (LAHR) 1989-1992 (Box 3)
  - Lansing Lesbian/Gay Hotline: Hotline Training Manual, Undated (Box 3)
  - Legal
    - Adrian (MI) Public Indecency Cases/Judge Glaser Homophobia Complaints 1990 (Box 3)
    - AIDS Testing/Employment Case 1989-1990 (Box 3)
    - Custody Case 1989 (Box 3)
    - Holland (MI) Police Harassment Cases 1989-1990 (Box 3)
    - Grand Haven (MI) Sex Charges 1990 (Box 3)
    - Michigan Privacy Challenge
      - 1983-June 1988 (Box 3)
      - July 1988-1990 (Box 3)
    - Rest Stop Cases 1989-1990 (Box 3)
    - Rouge Park (Detroit, MI) Police Harassment Complaints 1989-1990 (Box 3)
  - Legislative 1980-1989
    - Michigan Criminal Sexual Conduct Bills circa 1980-1985 (Box 3)
    - Michigan H.B. 4113 (Box 3)
    - Michigan H.B. 4330, 4646, 4712 and 4754 (Box 3)
    - Michigan H.B. 5000 (Box 3)
    - Michigan H.B. 5012, 5061, 5062, 5105, and 5176 (Box 3)
    - Michigan H.B. 5176 and 5279 (Box 3)
    - Michigan H.B. 5281, 5300, 5318, and 5377 (Box 3)
    - Michigan H.B. 5448, 5542, 5552, and 5579 (Box 3)
    - Michigan H.B. 5678-5681 and 5789 (Box 3)
    - Michigan H.B. 6222 (Box 3)
    - Michigan S.B. 115, 257, 330-341, 544, 579, 984, 1041 and Joint Resolution V (Box 3)
  - Lesbian Caucus 1990 (Box 3)
  - Lesbian/Gay Civil Rights Activism 1977-1990 (Box 3)
  - Lesbian/Gay Organizations in Michigan's Upper Peninsula 1992 (Box 3)
  - Lesbian Gay Foundation of Michigan (Box 3)
    (see MOHR Foundation)
  - Lobby Registration, State of Michigan 1989 (Box 3)
  - Lobbying Efforts 1986-1988 (Box 3)
  - Local Michigan Anti-Discrimination Ordinances 1986-1990 (Box 3)
  - March On Washington 1993 (Box 3)
  - Mayor's Advisory Board on Issues of Lesbian, Gay and Bisexual Citizens (Lansing, MI) 1992-1993 (Box 3)
  - Media Values Project 1990s (Box 3)
  - Membership Survey 1994 (Box 3)
  - Men of Color Motivational Group. Brochure Undated (Box 3)
  - Michigan Campaign for Human Dignity 1993 (Box 3)
  - Michigan Fights the Right Workshop 1993 (Box 3)
  - Michigan Human Rights Campaign Committee 1985-1989 (Box 3)
  - Michigan Insurance Bureau (Position on AIDS coverage) 1988-1989 (Box 3)
  - Michigan Lesbian and Gay Democratic Caucus 1988-1991 (Box 3)
  - Michigan Lesbian Health Survey 1989-1991 (Box 4)
  - Michigan Lobby Day for Lesbian-Gay Rights 1987 (Box 4)
  - Michigan State University Harassment Complaints 1989-1990 (Box 4)
  - MOHR Development Fund 1989-1990 (Box 4)
  - MOHR Foundation 1983-1991 (Box 4)
    (after January 27, 1991 Lesbian Gay Foundation of Michigan)
  - MOHR Music Festival 1986-1987 (Box 4)
  - MOHR Newsletter 1989-1990 (Box 4)
  - MOHR Petitions Undated (Box 4)
  - MOHRnet 1990 (Box 4)
  - Motor City Business Forum. Directory 1990-1991 (Box 4)
  - National Committee on U.S. Corrections (Farmington, MI) 1991 (Box 4)
  - New Generations Youth Support Group. Brochure Undated (Box 4)
  - Phillip Morris Boycott 1990 (Box 4)
  - Press Releases 1989-1992 (Box 4)
  - Pride Parade
    - 1986-1990 (Box 4)
    - 1991-1994 (Box 4)
    - Proclamations 1986-1991 (Box 4)
  - Sexual Orientation and Affectional Preference. Report of the Family and Sexuality Task Force, Michigan House of Representatives, 1982 (Box 4)
  - Some of Us (Cable T.V. production), 1985-1987 (Box 4)
  - Southeastern Michigan AIDS Coordinating Council. Proceedings 1991-1993 (Box 4)
  - Student Papers, Social Work 691 (Sexual Orientation). Wayne State University Fall 1992 (Box 4)
  - Triangle Foundations 1992-1993 (Box 4)
  - Wellness Networks 1985, 1992 (Box 4)
- Clippings
  The Clipping series ([199?], .9 linear feet) includes the M.O.H.R. clippings file, mostly from Michigan newspapers, of articles of interest to the organization's membership. This series has been retained exactly as it was organized by M.O.H.R., including the subject headings within the series.
  - Acceptance/Straight Support (Box 4)
  - AIDS
    - AIDS in Women (Box 4)
    - Disclosure (Box 4)
    - Discrimination and Protection from Discrimination (Box 4)
    - Education On (Box 4)
    - Efforts to Combat AIDS (Box 4)
    - Entertainment Concerning (Box 4)
    - Epidemiology and Prognostications (Box 4)
    - Famous People With (Box 4)
    - HIV Transmission (Box 4)
    - Hysteria (Box 4)
    - Insurance (Box 4)
    - Living With AIDS (Box 4)
    - Mandatory HIV Testing (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 4)
    - Politics (Box 4)
    - The Quilt (Box 4)
  - Bisexuality (Box 4)
  - Boycotts (Box 4)
  - Child Custody, Adoption (Box 4)
  - Civil/Human Rights (Box 4)
  - Clinton, Bill and L/G Community (Box 4)
  - Colorado's Amendment 2 (Box 4)
  - "Colorado Style" Proposals (Box 4)
  - Coming Out (Box 4)
  - Cracker Barrel (Box 4)
  - Domestic Partnerships/Gay Marriages
    - I (Box 4)
    - II (Box 4)
  - Education on Homosexuality (Box 4)
  - Elections (Box 4)
  - Entertainment (Box 4)
  - Etiology and Physiology of Sexual Orientation (Box 4)
  - Families (Box 5)
  - "For Better or for Worse": Gay Series and Reaction (Box 5)
  - Gay Politicians (Box 5)
  - Gender Equality (Box 5)
  - Genital Mutilation (Box 5)
  - Hate Crimes (Box 5)
  - Hatred/Homophobia (Box 5)
  - History and General Status of Gay Community (Box 5)
  - Lansing (Box 5)
  - Lansing State Journal (Box 5)
  - Legislation: Gay Rights, State of Michigan (Box 5)
  - Lesbian-Gay Male Relations (Box 5)
  - Lesbian/Women's Health (Box 5)
  - Lesbians: General Information (Box 5)
  - Media Portrayal/Coverage of Gays (Box 5)
  - Military
    - I (Box 5)
    - II (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 5)
  - Outing (Box 5)
  - Opinion
    - Letters to Editor (Box 5)
    - Op-Ed Columns (Box 5)
  - Parents of LesBiGays (Box 5)
  - Price, Deb (Box 5)
    (some of her columns may be filed elsewhere)
  - Queer Nation, ACT-UP, Lesbian Avengers (Box 5)
  - Religion (Box 5)
  - Seniors and Aging (Box 5)
  - Sex Education (Box 5)
  - Sexual Harassment/Violence (Box 5)
  - Sodomy Laws/Sex Crimes (Box 5)
  - Teenagers (Box 5)
  - Violence (Box 5)
- Robert Lundy (Legislation Officer) Files 1974-1994
  The Robert Lundy series (1974-1994, 3 linear feet) was donated to the library in 1998 and 2001 by Robert Lundy. It contains his files on legislative bills, his files relating to M.O.H. R. specifically, and his alphabetical topical files on issues, organizations and events with which he was active in his capacity as M.O.H.R.'s legislation officer.
  - Legislative Bills (Box 5)
    - Abstinence Instruction (S.B. 709) 1989 (Box 5)
    - AIDS Bill Votes (various) 1986 (Box 5)
    - AIDS: Blood Donors (H.B. 4992) 1987 (Box 5)
    - AIDS: Criminal Penalty (H.B. 4550) 1987 (Box 5)
    - AIDS Education for Health Instructors (H.B. 5188) 1987-1988 (Box 5)
    - AIDS Education in Schools (S.B. 115, Act 185 of 1987) 1987-1988 (Box 5)
    - AIDS Education for School Personnel (H.B. 4073, Act 139 of 1990) 1989-1990 (Box 5)
    - AIDS Hospital (H.B. 4842) 1989 (Box 5)
    - AIDS Insurance Buy-In Program (H.B. 5448?) 1989-1990 (Box 5)
    - AIDS: Medical Records (H.B. 5125) 1987 (Box 5)
    - AIDS: Physician Reporting (S.B. 632) 1987 (Box 5)
    - AIDS: Prisons (H.B. 4028, Act 510) 1985-1988 (Box 5)
    - AIDS: Public Health Officials (H.B. 5023) 1987 (Box 5)
    - AIDS: Public Health Officials (H.B. 5026, Act 490) 1987-1988 (Box 5)
    - AIDS Seropositivity Reporting and Contact Tracing (H.B. 4103, Act 489) 1986-1988 (Box 5)
    - AIDS: Spousal Notification (H.B. 4880) and AIDS: Physician-Patient Privilege (H.B. 4879) 1987-1988 (Box 5)
    - AIDS Testing, Implants and Insemination (H.B. 4980, Act 487) 1986-1988 (Box 5)
    - Arrestee AIDS Testing (H.B. 4008, Act 471) 1986-1988 (Box 5)
    - Ban on Funding of AIDS Patient Care in Cities (H.B. 4908) 1989 (Box 5)
    - Butyl Nitrate Ban (H.B. 4028) 1989 (Box 5)
    - Civil Liberties (H.B. 6635) (includes some H.B. 4251) 1978 (Box 5)
    - "Club" Regulations (S.B. 109) 1985 (Box 5)
    - Contact Tracing Required Before Parole (H.B. 4209) 1989 (Box 5)
    - Criminalizing Failure to Disclose HIV Status (H.B. 5536) 1988 (Box 5)
    - Delicensure for Immoral Conduct (H.B. 5256) 1987-1988 (Box 5)
    - Department of Corrections Appropriations (S.B. 763) 1988 (Box 5)
    - Designating AIDS as a "Hazardous Communicable Disease" (S.B. 521) 1987 (Box 5)
    - Disability Coverage, Preexisting Condition (H.B. 4537-4538; 4695-4696) 1989 (Box 5)
    - Domestic Relations (H.B. 4292) 1989-1990 (Box 5)
    - Durable Power of Attorney (H.B. 4016) 1987-1990 (Box 5)
    - Hate Crimes Statistics (H.B. 5105) 1991-1992 (Box 5)
    - HIV Confidentiality (S.B. 504, H.B. 4959, Act 174 of 1989) 1989 (Box 5)
    - HIV Disclosure, Foster Children (H.B. 5131, Act 271 of 1989) 1989 (Box 5)
    - HIV Infection, Duty to Warn (H.B. 4956) 1989 (Box 5)
    - HIV Testing, Corrections Officers (H.B. 5144) 1989 (Box 5)
    - HIV Testing of Sexual Offenders (H.B. 5417, S.B. 748) 1988 (Box 5)
    - HIV Testing of Those Charged with Sexual Assault (S.B. 984) 1988 (Box 5)
    - Inheritance Taxes (S.B. 1) 1989-1990 (Box 5)
    - Insurance Non-discrimination (H.B. 4951) 1988-1990 (Box 5)
    - Involuntary HIV Testing of Exposed Officers (S.B. 519) 1989 (Box 11)
    - Involuntary HIV Testing of Hospital Patients (S.B. 579) 1989-1990 (Box 11)
    - Library Privacy (H.B. 5066) 1981-1982 (Box 11)
    - Living Will (H.B. 4174, S.B. 135) 1989-1990 (Box 11)
    - Mandatory HIV Testing of Emergency Patients (H.B. 5326, S.B. 985) 1987-1988 (Box 11)
    - Marriage AIDS Testing (H.B. 4034, S.B. 33) 1986-1988 (Box 11)
    - Michigan Health Initiative (S.B. 544-546., H.B. 5151-5153, Act 258 of 1987) 1987-1988 (Box 11)
    - Minority Health (H.B. 4671) 1989 (Box 11)
    - Obscenity Display (H.B. 5579) 1985-1986 (Box 11)
    - Omnibus AIDS Bill (S.B. 1041, Act 491) 1988 (Box 11)
    - Prisoner AIDS Testing (S.B. 827) 1988 (Box 11)
    - Prisoner Parole Contact Tracing (H.B. 4717) 1987 (Box 11)
    - Reasons to Oppose (Various Bills), ACLU and MOHR Positions 1988, undated (Box 11)
    - Religious Exception to Premarital AIDS Counseling (S.B. 535) 1989-1990 (Box 11)
    - Reporting AIDS Seropositivity to School Authorities (H.B. 4998) 1987 (Box 11)
    - Teacher Decertification (H.B. 4347) 1987 (Box 11)
    - Universal Health Care (S.B. 97) 1989 (Box 11)
  - MOHR Files
    - Addresses 1980-1987 (Box 11)
    - Annual Conference 1980-1985 (Box 11)
    - Annual Report 1977-1984 (Box 11)
    - "Answers to Parents Questions About Homosexuality" Pamphlet (Box 11)
    - Articles of Incorporation 1983 (Box 11)
    - Blanchard Telegram 1982 (Box 11)
    - Board Meeting Minutes 1978-1988 (Box 11)
    - Budget 1989 (Box 11)
    - Bylaws and Bylaw Amendments 1979-1988, undated (Box 11)
    - Civil Service Commission 1981 (Box 11)
    - "Coming Out" Pamphlet (Box 11)
    - Correspondence
      - Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) 1979-1980 (Box 11)
      - Tom Downs (lobbyist for MOHR) 1987 (Box 11)
      - Federal Communications Commission 1983 (Box 11)
      - Richard Headlee 1982 (Box 11)
      - Internal Revenue Service (IRS) 1978 (Box 11)
      - Lansing City Council, Re: Mayor's harassment ordinance 1980 (Box 11)
    - Department of Civil Rights "Challence 150" Conference, Response to 1987 (Box 11)
    - Detroit Committee/ Detroit Human Rights Ordinance 1977-1979 (Box 11)
    - Detroit Lesbian/ Gay Community Center 1987-1989 (Box 11)
    - Donor Pledges 1983, undated (Box 11)